W.D. Lowther Civil War Letters, 1863-1864
University of Houston Libraries
W. D. Lowther Civil War Letters
June 1863-May 1864
Lowther, W.D.
1970-004
W.D. Lowther was a member of Company D, 2nd Texas Brigade, 17th Consolidated Regiment in the Confederate Army. The Lowther collection consists of 13 fetters from dated from June, 1863 through May of 1864.
1 box; 26 items
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Biographical Note
W.D. Lowther was a member of Company D, 2nd Texas Brigade, 17th Consolidated Regiment in the Confederate Army. This company was attached to Fluornoy's Regiment sometime in 1863, and approximately 25 men from Walker's division were with them, as well.
Scope and Contents
The Lowther collection consists of 13 letters from Confederate soldier W.D. Lowther to his fiancee, Phronie or Fronie Autry, in Texas during the United States Civil War. Dated from June, 1863 through May of 1864, these handwritten letters are all accompanied by typed transcriptions, and a few folders contain handwritten transcripts, as well.
Acquisition
The collection was a gift of Mr. William Kilgarlin in February, 1970.
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Subjects (Persons)
Lowther, W.D.
Subjects
Confederate States of America. Army. Texas Brigade; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Regimental histories -- Texas Brigade; Texas -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives, Confederate.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Social aspects.
Formats
Correspondence
Detailed Description
  - Letter to Frona, Apr. 24, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Phrona, June 9, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Fronie, June 16, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter to Fronie, June 23, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Phronie, July 26, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter to Phronie, Aug. 24, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter to Phronie, Sept. 14, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter to Phronie, Nov. 26, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter to Phronie, Dec. 13, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter to Phronie, Dec. 28, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter to Phronie, Jan. 25, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter to Phronie, May 24, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 12)